Welcome to this exercise task about Petri
Nets.
And in this case, we have been given three
Petri Nets and we shall find all the reasons
why these Petri Nets are not correct.
We already know that these Petri Nets are
not correct.
And therefore, we have to check each one of them
for reasons that make them invalid.
And within the first Petri Net, we can see
for instance that here, a transition is followed
by another transition.
So, t1 leads to t4.
And this is not valid because we have to switch
always between places and transitions.
As we don't do this here, we have one reason
that there is a transition between t2 and
t4 which makes it invalid.
And when we check further, we see that there
is another such reason for this Petri Net
to be invalid.
In this case, there is an edge between t4
and t1 and as there are no connections allowed
between transitions itself, this is a violation
and makes the Petri Net invalid.
We can check this Petri Net further and see
that now, there is always a place, followed
by a transition by connecting these edges.
And that is why if these actions are removed,
it would be a valid Petri Net.
Now, we can check the second Petri Net.
And here we see that we have always place
followed by transition and place when we check
this Petri Net.
So, there are no connections between transitions
or places themselves.
But there is another issue, and this concerns
the weight which is given here because
negative weights are not allowed at these
edges between places to transitions or transitions
to places.
And that is why this is not valid, the second
Petri Net.
And when we see the third Petri Net and look
what's wrong here, then we see a claim that
we had here edges between transitions and
another transition.
Now, we have an edge between a place and another
place.
This edge here is violating this Petri Net
from being correct.
And there is another problem within this Petri
Net and this concerns the transition or the
edges between place one and transition one.
When we look into this Petri Net, we see that
both edges are going from s1 to t1.
And this is a problem, because it just simply
does not make any sense for two edges to be
existing there because there's no mathematical
representation within our definition of Petri
Nets.
So, if there would be an edge with the weight
of three, everything would be alright, but
having two separate edges does not make any
sense between s1 and t1.
And this should be all reasons that can be
found within these Petri Nets.
So, we're basically done with this task when
you write all these reasons down.